Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records 5948
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records
1973-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWSDU)
RWSDU Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union
5948
3.22 cubic feet
3.2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5736600
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 14, 2001
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Between 1933 and 1957, 1199 functioned as a drugstore local with its membership growing to 5,000 workers employed in independent and chain drugstores throughout the New York metropolitan area. With its success in organizing workers in Montefiore Hospital in New York City, the union began a massive campaign to organize workers in voluntary and non-profit hospitals in the New York area, a large proportion of whom were black or Hispanic.
In 1973, the national union was established with locals in other states, including Pennsylvania, Maryland, South and North Carolina, Connecticut, New Jersey, and Massachusetts. The union combined organizing efforts with civil rights organizations, in an effort to achieve mutual political goals. Throughout the period of these records, the union was led by Leon Davis (president of Local 1199 and of the national union) whose administration guided the union's political and social activities.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5995: Retail, Wholesale, And Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug And Hospital Employees Union (New York, N.Y.) Rochester, N.Y.. Additional Records 5206: Local 1199 Records
Health facilities -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union (New York, N.Y.); Service Employees International Union. District 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.)
5736600
- Buttons and Bumper stickers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1199, SEIU, AFL-CIO
- Calendars, Rochester 1199, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Calendars, Rochester Labor, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Center of Concern Newsletters, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women-American Family Celebration Local Action Kit, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  5/14/1988
- Collective Bargaining and Health Care - SEIU Research Department, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Day Care Issues-Monroe County Day Care Consortium, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Merger Agreement between SEIU and NUHHCE and Health Care Davison By-Laws (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Muehlenkamp, Robert Slide Presentation at Cornell Organizers Forum, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  10/25/1991
- National Benefit Fund for Hospital and Health Care Employees Financial Reports, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Report to National Union Executive Board, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  10/28/1978
- National Pension/Benefit Funds for Hospital and Health Care Employees 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- National Union Financial Reports-Exec Board Meeting, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees -Second Convention Financial Reports, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  12/10-13/75
- Third Convention Financial Reports, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Third Convention Wage Standards and Organizational Activities Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fourth Convention Officers Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  12/5/1979
- Fourth Convention Financial Reports, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Fourth Convention Wage Standards and Organizational Activities Report (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Fifth Convention, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Seventh Convention, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  12/9-12/87
- Officers Report to the National Union Convention, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- New England Health Care Employees, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- New England Health Care Employees Welfare Fund, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Occupational Disease in NYS-Proposal for a Statewide Network of Occupational Disease Diagnosis and Prevention Centers, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  12/9/1986
- Occupational Health Matters, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  v.1:no.1 (1986:Spring)
- Popper, Bruce, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Rochester Area Labor and Religion Conference, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Rivera, Dennis Profile 12/10/90 from The New Yorker, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Adams Drug Co/1199 New England Division, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Anthony L. Jordan Health Center/1199, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Association of Voluntary Homes/1199, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Beth Israel Medical Center/Registered Nurses of 1199, 1980-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Brookdale Hospital Medical Center/Registered Nurses Division of 1199, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Builders Exchange of Rochester/Carpenters Local 85, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Continuing Developmental Services/1199, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital/General Service Employees Union, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  12/31/1991
- Davenport Osteopathic Hospital/NUHHCE, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- DeGraff Memorial Hospital/CWA, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Empire State and Long Island Pharmaceutical Societies/1199 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- GMC Rochester Division/UAW 1097, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Group Health Cooperative of Puget Sound/Group Health Registered Nurses/ 1199, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Hurley Medical Center/Registered Nurses Organization, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Johns Hopkins Hospital/1199E, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Kaiser Foundation Hospitals/Office and Professional employees International Union Local 30, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lakeshore Nursing Home/1199, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of New York/1199, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Madison General Hospital/1199W, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Monroe, County of/CSEA, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mount Clemens General Hospital/1199M, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- National Benefit Fund for Hospital and Health Care Employees/New England Health Care Employees Welfare Fund, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- New York, State of/CSEA Institutional Services Unit, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Office and Professional Employees International Union Local 30-Standard Union Office Agreement, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Philadelphia College of Osteopathic Medicine/1199, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Psychiatric Institute of Washington DC/CWA, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Regional Transit Service/ Amalgamated Transit Union local 282, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Rochester City School District/BENTE/AFSCME 2419, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Rochester Labor Council Constitution and By-Laws, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Rochester Labor Council-Directories of Local Unions, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Rochester Telephone Corp./CWA, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- St. Claire's Hospital/1199, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- San Francisco, City and County of/SEIU locals 250, 535 & 790, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Schlegel Corp. Rochester Division/ACTWU, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- SEIU Constitution and By-Laws, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Southeastern Michigan Chapter American Red Cross/1199M, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Strong Memorial Hospital/1199, 1974-1992 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- University of Rochester/1199, 1975-1992 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Volunteers of America Adult Care Facility/ 1199, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Women and Infants Hospital of Rhode Island/1199, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Xerox Corp/ACWA local 14A, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- 1199 Financial Report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1199 national union contracts/Office Procedure Manual, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 1199 Newsletters, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 1199 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  June 1989.
- 1199, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1199 Constitution, 1973-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Includes amended versions
- 1199E bylaws (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1199 Newspaper Clippings, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- New England Health Care Employees of 1199 bylaws, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1199 Rochester Newspaper Clips, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1199 Publicity (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 1199 Wage Standards and Organizational Activities Reports, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  12/79.
- Report to 1199 Executive Council, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  11/6/1978
- SEIU/1199 National Leadership Conference, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  6/5/1981
- SEIU Resources Catalog, Film and Video Catalog, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Service Employees Union Magazine, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- SEIU Settlements Report, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  First half of 1989
- Fiscal Year 1990 Federal Budget: Impact on SEIU Members, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- The Hidden Story of Taxpayer Subsidies for Low Wage Employer's Public Policy Department, SEIU, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- "Employer Paid health Insurance is Disappearing" SEIU Public Policy Department, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Service Employees, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  v.45/46 (1986)
- SEIU COPE, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- SEIU Legislative Action Packet 101st Congress, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Resolutions Committee Submissions, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- SEIU Health and Welfare/National Pension Funds, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- The Safety Link Vol. 3 No. 2 April 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  v.3:no.2 (1992:Apr.)
- SEIU, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- 1992 SEIU Convention (Box 3, Folder 28)
- University of Rochester NYSDH Planning Grant-First Report, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  1/29/1988
- Second Report, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  4/29/1988
- Final Report, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  6/30/1988
- Update, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  1990-92 Issues
- Unlabeled materials (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Images of Labor -- incl. Malcolm X & A Philip Randolph (Box 4)
- Bread and Roses (Box 5)